ALEX LAM

0424987981 • alexlam1994@live.com

Summary

I would like to continue to develop my clinical skills while creating a fun learning environment for patients and helping them through their challenges. I am very well qualified and would be an asset to the hospital because of my experience working as a pharmacist manager for Chemist Warehouse.



EDUCATION

PSA Immunisation Training ◆Sydney, NSW (2020)

Pharmaceutical Society of Australia ◆ Sydney, NSW (2016)

Graduate Certificate in Applied Pharmacy Practice

University of Sydney ◆ Camperdown/Darlinghurst, NSW (2015)

Bachelor of Pharmacy

St Johns Park High School ◆ Greenfield Park (2011)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Chemist Warehouse, Sydney NSW (2012 - present)

Australia's largest pharmacy retailer with nearly 9,500 staff members

Pharmacy Student / Pharmacist-in-charge / Pharmacist Manager

- Maintain records of all transactions of the pharmacy necessary to ensure accurate control over and accountability for all dugs as required by NSW and federal laws, rules and regulations.
- Ensure legal operation of the pharmacy, including meeting all inspection and other requirements of state and federal laws, rules, and regulations governing pharmacy operations.
- Fill prescriptions for patients and submit appropriate claims for third-party reimbursement.
- Consult with physicians and nurses regarding pharmaceutical questions.
- Provide functional supervision to professionals and support staff in the pharmacy including training, assigning duties and providing input for performance evaluations.

Committed to Coaching, Canley Heights NSW (2011-2013)

Dedicated coaching team aimed to provide the best quality of education to primary and secondary students

Coach/Tutor

- Organising and educating HSC level mathematics to students.
- Ensured the productive learning and safety of students within a dynamic classroom.
- Enforced all policies and procedures pertaining to classroom rules while maintaining an enjoyable learning environment.

LEADERSHIP ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

Flu Clinic Coordinator and Vaccinator ◆ Flu Vaccination program at Chemist Warehouse Hurstville and Haymarket

Campaigner for Liptember ◆ Australian Charities and Not-for-profit Commission

Retail Manager ◆ Preparing and Executing promotions

Member ◆ Sydney University Pharmacy Association (SUPA) ◆ Camperdown/Darlinghurst (2012 – 2015)

Member ◆ Pharmaceutical Society of Australia (PSA) ◆ (2012 – present)

SKILLS

MedScope HMR Med Management Software ◆ Practicare Dose Administration Aid Software ◆ MyScripts Dispensing Software

Proficient in Microsoft Office: MS Word ◆ MS PowerPoint ◆ MS Excel ◆ MS Outlook

◆Managing Stock Inventory (PharmX Software)

◆ Social Media: Facebook ◆ WhatsApp ◆ LinkedIn

Bilingual: fluent in English and Cantonese